Omar Vasquez Duque

525 Day St, San Francisco. CA 94131

📱 650-833-9898 | 🗷 omarvd@stanford.edu | 🧥 omarvd.github.io | 🖸 github.com/omarvd | 🛅 www.linkedin.com/in/omarvd | 📚 Google Scholar

Personal Profile

I am a research fellow at the Stanford Rock Center for Corporate Governance and the Stanford Olin Program in Law and Economics. My research applies behavioral insights to competition policy, corporate governance, and economic regulation. I am especially interested in empirically assessing the impact of law and its policy implications. I have formal training in law, economic theory, econometrics, and behavioral science. This is a short version of my CV. For a complete list of publications and grants, please go to my GitHub website.

Education

Stanford Law School Stanford, CA

Doctorate in Juridical Sciences (J.S.D.)

Sept 2018 - June 2023

- Thesis: Essays in Competition Law and Economics
- · Doctoral Committee: Rob MacCoun (chair), John Donohue, Jacob Goldin, and Doug Melamed
- Courses: Advanced Antitrust, Law and Economics, Law and Psychology, Law and Society, Research Design for Empirical Legal Studies, Social Psychology and Public Policy, Statistical Inference in Law

Stanford University Stanford, CA

Master of Arts in Economics (M.A.)

Sept 2018 - June 2022

- GPA: 3.86
- Courses: Behavioral Economics, Causal Inference for Social Sciences, Health Economics, Machine Learning, Microeconomics, Natural Language Processing for Social Sciences, Positive Political Theory and the Law, Regression Models, Statistical Methods for Social and Behavioral Sciences

Harvard Law School Cambridge, MA

Master's of Laws (LL.M.)

Aug 2015 - June 2016

- · RA for Professor Einer Elhauge; Editor, Journal of Law and Public Policy and Business Law Review
- Courses: Administrative Law; Antitrust; Behavioral Law and Economics and Public Policy; Conceptions of Legal Entities; Controlling Shareholders; Consumer Contracts; Empirical Methods; Law and Economics; Law, Economics, and Psychology

University of Chile Santiago, Chile

Bachelor in Law and Social Sciences (LL.B.)

March 2006 - Nov 2013

- Summa cum laude
- TA of Antitrust Law, Corporations, Microeconomics, Law and Economics, Research Assistant for Santiago Montt at the Center for Regulation and Competition (RegCom)
- Courses: Administrative Law, Antitrust, Bankruptcy, Civil Procedure, Commercial Contracts, Contracts, Corporations, Criminal Law, Environmental Law, Family Law, History of Law, International Commercial Contracts, International Private Law, International Public Law, Jurisprudence, Labor Law, Latin, Law and Economics, Macroeconomics, Microeconomics, Moral Philosophy, Property, Public Utilities, Roman Law, State Liability, Tax Law, Torts

Work Experience

Stanford University Stanford, CA

Instructor, Teaching Assistant, Research Assistant

Sept 2020 - June 2023

- Instructor of Law and Economics (Law and Economics, Econ 154, PublPol 106/206) Spring guarters of 2021 and 2022
- Teaching Assistant for Professor Mitchell A. Polinsky (Economic Analysis of Law, LAW 7502) since 2019
- Teaching Assistant for Professor Robert J. MacCoun (Law and Psychology, LAW 3518) since 2020
- Research Assistant for Professors Amalia Kessler, Lawrence M. Friedman, and Robert J. MacCoun

Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development

Mexico City, Mexico

Competition Expert

July 2016 - Aug 2017

- Competition assessment of the Mexican pharmaceutical sector
- Applied the OECD Competition Assessment Toolkit to the Mexican Pharmaceutical Sector. This project entailed mapping all the relevant laws, building a database of relevant legislation, meeting with the main industry's stakeholders, analyzing the merit of hundreds of restrictions to competition in the sector, and drafting a final report with policy recommendations, which is available here

Fiscalia Nacional Economica

Santiago, Chile

Antitrust Enforcer

April 2013 - Aug 2015

- Case handler, Abuse of Dominance Division.
- Specialized in analysis of financial markets, unregulated markets and advocacy strategies.

JANUARY 9, 2023

Selected Publications _____

- 2022. Active Choice vs. Inertia? An Exploratory Assessment of the European Microsoft Case's Choice Screen, *Journal of Competition Law and Economics* (2022).
- 2021. Una Introducción al Análisis Económico del Derecho (An Introduction to the Economic Analysis of Law). Valencia, Spain. *Tirant lo Blanch*. Foreword by Professor A. Mitchell Polinsky. Review by Professor Florencia Marotta-Wurgler (book, whole)
- 2021. Can Data Exploitation be Properly Addressed by Competition Law? A Note of Caution, February 2021, *Concurrences* N° 1-2021, Art. N° 98791, pp. 75-82 (coauthored with Jörg Hoffmann)
- 2021. Buyer Beware: An Exploratory Assessment of the New Chilean Food Labeling Model. *Hastings International and Comparative Law Review*. V.44, 2. Summer Issue: 144-165
- 2020. No Alarms and Many Surprises: Salience as a Basis for Excessive Pricing Intervention in an Antitrust Context. *Journal of Competition Law and Economics*. Volume 16, Issue 4, December 2020, pp. 552–571
- 2018. Why do Most People Follow the Default Matrimonial Property Regime in Chile? Economic Analysis of Law Review, 2018 V. 9, 2: 232-258.
- 2017. The Costs of Loyalty: On Loyalty Rewards and Consumer Welfare. Economic Analysis of Law Review, V. 8, 2: 409-445.

You may find a complete list of publications in my GitHub.

Skills

Programming R (Tidyverse library), SQL, Python

Miscellaneous LaTeX (Overleaf/R Markdown), Tableau, Microsoft Office, Git, Stata

Achievements

2022-2023 George P. Shultz Dissertation Fellowship , Stanford Institute for Eco	nomic Policy Research (SIEPR)	Stanford, CA
2018-2023 Fellowship in Law and Economics, John M. Olin Program in Law and	l Economics	Stanford, CA
2018-2023 Summer Research Fellowship , John M. Olin Program in Law and Eco	onomics	Stanford, CA
2021-2022 Lieberman Fellowship , Stanford VPGE		Stanford, CA
June 2016 Summer academic fellow, Harvard Law School		Cambridge, MA

Referee_

2022-	Journal of Competition Law and Economics, Oxford University Press	Oxford, UK
2021-	European Journal of Law and Economics, Springer	Berlin, GE
2020-	Journal of Antitrust Enforcement, Oxford University Press	Oxford, UK

Languages _____

English Professional proficiency
Spanish Native proficiency
French Beginner

German Beginner

References

John J. Donohue	Wendell and Carlsmith Professor of Law, Stanford Law School. donohue@law.stanford.edu T. 650 721 6339
Jacob S. Goldin	Richard M. Lipton Professor of Tax Law, University of Chicago Law School. jsgoldin@uchicago.edu T.773 702 9494
Robert J. MacCoun	James and Patricia Kowal Professor of Law, Stanford Law School. rmaccoun@stanford.edu T. 650 721 3011
A. Douglas Melamed	Scholar in Residence, Stanford Law School. dmelamed@law.stanford.edu T. 650 743 7204
A. Mitchell Polinsky	Josephine Scott Crocker Professor of Law, Stanford Law School. polinsky@stanford.edu T. 650 743 7204
Gregory Rosston	Director Public Policy Program, Stanford University. grosston@stanford.edu T. 650 725 0722
D. Daniel Sokol	Professor of Law, University of Southern California. dsokol@usc.edu T. 202 626 3600

JANUARY 9, 2023 2